<!-- $Id$ -->
<Chapter Label="Intro">
<Heading>Introduction</Heading>    

<Section Label="Aims">
<Heading>General aims</Heading>

Let <M>KG</M> be a group algebra of a finite <M>p</M>-group <M>G</M>
over the field <M>K</M> of characteristic <M>p</M>, and let <M>V(KG)</M>
be the normalized unit group of <M>KG</M>. 

The pc-presentation of the group <M>V(KG)</M> 
can be computed using the &GAP; package &LAGUNA;
(<URL>http://ukrgap.exponenta.ru/laguna.htm</URL>), but for groups of
orders 64 and bigger this computation will already take a lot of time. 
<P/>

The &UnitLib; package is an extension of the &LAGUNA; package that is 
aimed on this problem. It contains the library of normalized unit groups
of modular group algebras of finite <M>p</M>-groups over the field
of <M>p</M> elements. This allows the user to retrieve the pre-computed
group from the library instead of the long-time computation. The group
created with &UnitLib; will have the same properties and attributes as
the one computed with &LAGUNA;.
<P/>

The current version of &UnitLib; contains normalized unit groups 
<M>V(KG)</M> for all <M>p</M>-groups of order not greater than 128.
<P/>

</Section>


<Section Label="Install">
<Heading>Installation and system requirements</Heading>

Libraries of normalized unit groups of groups of orders less than 128
will be available in any operating system. The library for groups of order
128 was compressed using <File>gzip</File> program and, therefore, will be 
available only in UNIX-type systems (including UNIX-installation in Mac OS X
and Cygwin installation in Windows). 
<P/>
 
&UnitLib; is designed for &GAP;4.4 and no compatibility with previous 
releases of &GAP;4 is guaranteed. 
<P/>

Because the &UnitLib; is an extension of the &LAGUNA; package, you must
have the &LAGUNA; package installed. You can obtain it from the &GAP; 
homepage or from its homepage 
<URL>http://ukrgap.exponenta.ru/laguna.htm</URL>.
<P/>

To use the &UnitLib; online help it is necessary to install the &GAP;4 package 
&GAPDoc; by Frank L\"ubeck and Max Neunh\"offer, which is available from the 
&GAP; homepage or from 
<URL>http://www.math.rwth-aachen.de/~Frank.Luebeck/GAPDoc/</URL>.
<P/> 

&UnitLib; is distributed in standard formats
(<File>zoo</File>, <File>tar.gz</File>, <File>tar.bz2</File>, 
<File>-win.zip</File>) and can be obtained the &GAP; homepage or from 
<URL>http://ukrgap.exponenta.ru/unitlib.htm</URL>.
To unpack the archive <File>unitlib-1.0.zoo</File> you need the program 
<File>unzoo</File>, which can be obtained from the &GAP; homepage 
<URL>http://www.gap-system.org/</URL> (see section `Distribution').
To install &UnitLib;, copy this archive into the <File>pkg</File> 
subdirectory of your &GAP;4.4 installation. Then the subdirectory 
<File>unitlib</File> containing the package will be created in 
the <File>pkg</File> directory after the command
<C>unzoo -x unitlib-1.0.zoo</C>

</Section>

</Chapter>